all right thanks jared for showing up
for your first
first solution raising on science
absolutely we have a big topic i think
it
scared everyone else so an hour focused
conversation
on what could we come up with for
science
that 10 000 people could do with a
hundred thousand dollars that would give
us access to science
so we start for with roughly 15 minutes
or less
on um what it currently looks like so
my background is in science i have my
master's i do not have a master's degree
i have my undergraduate science i just
promoted myself
and i don't have a master's degree and
really to work in science you need to
have at least a master's really you need
a phd
and i was not dedicated enough to go on
and do that
i already knew i didn't want to work in
a lab and i didn't want to do field
studies
so um what does science look like to you
in the world
in your life science is interesting
um so i
for the last two years so i've been a
music producer in dj for 10 years
before this so i've not really been
um although i've i went to school at
lehigh university
in the integrated business and
engineering program so
i've had like a whole slew of
education but not necessarily any one
hard discipline um that i focused on too
much
so science to me um
i guess my biggest focus came about
two years ago when i was thinking about
my um project kubi which is
um it the the general idea behind this
is to kick-start personal growth in
people
and uh i was thinking about
what if people could get paid
to learn things what would the world
look like or what like an extrinsic um
kind of motivation to then jump start
this learning process then i'm like
what would they learn because the
information people are learning
that is like then then i got into sense
making of like what
what's even going on here and um
to me what really
i think might be important in science
is um
the ability for people to
decentralize it in in one way or another
um because right now science is
funded by x y or z
and that funding determines
a lot i mean i i don't know nearly
enough about
the um the specific inner workings of
science but i do know that
when there is a market dynamic
and capitalistic drive to
to do something there can always
there's an incentive for
misinformation and um
if there is a way to shift
shift the shift the process
such that a large group of people could
decide
what was important to research then fund
that research
and then have people like like that
would be a
an interesting way like an interesting
dynamic i think
um so i've kind of thought about this a
little bit
but it wasn't really yeah that's like
the
proto ideas i've had in my head about
science
um thanks um i'll share mine and you
kind of combine
the next part too which is when we share
our beautiful vision of the future we
love science
oh okay great but we all do that we all
we all do that the entire time it's like
they always just kind of
yeah yeah but this part so my life like
i said i have an undergrad degree in
science i went to
the university of british columbia and i
did an integrated science degree in
genetics
so the super tiny and ecology the super
big and i found it weird when i was
there because
you can do an integrated science degree
but none of the professors were like
those two things aren't related like
what do you mean they're not related
they're like the micro in the macro and
i did a minor
a minor in economics because i was like
and i need to know that in the world in
order to be able to actually do
something
and then in my third year i got
diagnosed with brain tumors and i went
from like being the scientist to being
the
the patient and realizing how broken our
medical system is
how you're expected to hand your life
over to these doctors who are gods but
they really don't have information they
don't know
i'm like well why did my body create
these why would you even want to know
that just like burn them out cut them
out give them like
i'm like well i want to know i want to
know where it came from and this
lifelong journey now over the last
really almost well
15 years of um the more i concentrate on
having to be the person who figures out
my health the worse it gets because of
placebo effect
and feeling like the overwhelm of not
being able to like
have access to the science mentally
financially and just it's not there
um and so i'm very frustrated with the
level of
that there's a there's a scientific
study that's published and then the
media takes hold of it and they give you
like
it's it's you know like like margin
margarine cures cancer murdering causes
cancer and it's not
we don't really have access to it
neither do the doctors
and then everything's behind a pay wall
and realizing the politics and the the
game a
crap that's all in science as well what
is funded
whether you're published is it like is
it is it if it's too inside the box
it doesn't get published because it's
not new and novel and if it's too
outside the box it breaks everything and
it doesn't get published
and so there's these powers that be that
decide if something
is allowed or not allowed and there's a
lot of
you know all of the isms come into place
the racism and sexism of people just
like not having
it's harder to get ahead with any of
those things which means we're stopping
science from happening that
right now during covet 19 there's a lot
of um
what is like open source science but
there's also a lot of proprietary behind
closed door science
and you know we want to be the ones with
a vaccine we want to be the one we want
to give you this drug instead of this
drug because this one has a five-year
patent and this one has you know a
10-year patent and we want to make money
no we need to figure out like if it's
there for science and health what is
what is going to give us the most
science and health and access to it and
so
as somebody whose brain has changed
right now no longer can
read a scientific paper and understand
it i want
access financially not behind the
paywall to the science but i also want
to explain to me like i'm a
fifth grader like i want it to be like
this is the study and this is what
happened and here's what we know from it
and um anyway i just also switched into
the next one so now we can naturally
switch into the next one
we would love it to look like what would
a beautiful game be scientific world
look like
and we don't need to match if we happen
to have completely polar opposite ones
that's fine yeah i can't imagine we do
well that i mean it's running really
similarly
um it's kind of in the same vein
like running parallel to the thoughts
i've had for a long time
on um
a tool for people to
a tool for people to access
ai vetted scientific
data straight from the source parsed
into easily consumable
micro learning formats if that that's
kind of a mouthful there but like
that was a vision i've had for a while
is
these studies just if we if we can even
assume that a study is worth looking at
let's let's forget about the who funded
it and all the other
the bs but
a lot of it has most most of the stuff
right now is
very um
it just doesn't it's it's not accessible
to uh the average person
it's it's it's a mess so if we could use
ai to go through
and understand the content
then spit it out in a
standardized or maybe not standardized
but
a simpler format to a person so whether
that be through
a small card or an interaction with
the ai you ask questions it gives you
answers
it could be a lot of different ways
i think that would be a really important
tool for the average person
to understand science a little bit
better and to actually have the ai
be able to go through all
of the scientific journals
and things that have that didn't make
publication but
are valid things you know and like
what that i don't know i just feel like
it's so important to
have a baseline of
all of that and to
process all of that knowledge bringing
into a
place that people can easily access it
um that that kind of vision
is there for me um and that's where like
i have a that connection to the
the um internet of intelligence i'll
send you that um
up so link we we did a the episode
before you
we did one with the inventor of the
internet of things
and he uh is working on
ais that understand human language and
can
do that so i i really want to long term
be able to
use this ai to help science
be more accessible to the average person
and cut out the middlemen for everything
great i mean i would love i don't
disagree with that i think and i watched
that episode by the way
oh great yeah um it was over my head
because i'm not i don't i'm like
i use like rhythms is like you know like
ai and algorithms will figure it out
without like it's like magic right like
i'm like someone else knows that but
they do
so it works but we're not quite there
yet right right
we don't have the trust and we don't
have and that's great this is the five
ten years in the future
and then the next one is the adjacent
possible so what i would love is open
source
science so scientists have access to
funding that isn't from
the for-profit places the people who are
deciding on what to fund like as
most of the cancer money research either
comes from the governments or from
people who've had loved ones die from
cancer
who funded and then it goes to a a
not-for-profit
company that then decides on funding
things that are for-profit and it's
it's just a whole broken mess so to be
able
to as somebody with a condition be part
of a cooperative that can say hey if
we're fundraising this money then we
should be able to decide what it goes to
does it go to figuring out how to live
with this does it go to figuring out how
to never get it does it go to figuring
out a cure
does it go to open source medication so
that you know there isn't this this
for-profit model
i want to be able to have access to
science in a usable understandable way
i want scientists to be able to publish
their their findings
including before long before it's ever
published
having a way to register
null experiments so you run an
experiment either has something novel
and you publish it or it doesn't
which we need to have that access to
that information and when it's done
for profit right if you have and any of
the pharmaceutical companies
run a study and then it comes back that
this thing's poison oh we'll just run it
again
like they don't have to register it and
then and then
crazy show you what that information is
that i want to have access to
and we're all data points and so to be
able to use my information of my
genetics of my
what i'm eating how my lifestyle is to
be able to see
what because you can't eat we're pieces
of data but we also can't
get anything in uh powerful from that
without being part of its study
and studies are so expensive and yet
we're all putting our stuff on social
media
if there was a way to actually say okay
these people all got this form of brain
cancer what do they have in common
and then it gives you the information to
then run a study and be like okay now we
need a proper double-blind study
but to be able to have access to that
information to be able to to
work with other people who have my same
conditions so that we
are have each other's back when we're in
front of the doctor
because there's a lot of bad medical
advice you get who know it's bad medical
advice because you've been in it for a
while and it's like no actually we all
disagree with you
like we've all decided like that is
poison for us
and when they're then the authority and
you're not you have to listen to them
like you
legally basically have to listen to them
or you get everything all your money
taken away
and yet they're put they're destroying
our our lives
and so to be able to see that in a more
in a way that both the doctor has access
to because they also have access to
stuff that i don't right they went to
medical school
but if they don't have access to the
information that shows our bodies as
ecosystems
shows us as part of the bigger ecosystem
and
can we can see well why why is my body
reacting in that way why is it creating
these things and be able to to undo it
to be able to have
easier this isn't quite science be able
to have
access to my lab tests right and
i just turned it back into science my
lab test and what i'm eating and my
genetics and and
be able to see my life we also able to
don't to donate in a safe way that
information to the pool
so we can see why are we getting cancer
why are
all the cancers clustered around this
geographical region that's interesting
to be able to have open source
laboratories like maker spaces where you
have
access to soil science and things that
you know you can just send in your soil
and send in your water sample and send
stuff in
and and have a way to access that so we
can see well is there arsenic in the
soil is there lead is there
is that in the water and to be able to
see those
then work through well now we have to
fix that right what do we plan to take
that out what do we have to get out of
the water supply
actually i mean i'm not into leaving
stuff up to powers to be in any way
shape or form anymore
i want i trust science i don't trust our
current science
i think it's very political and very
corrupt and so how can you trust it well
where's the null
science where's where's the big
long-term studies where's
like we can't keep polluting our earth
and expect to not get cancer
and disease and yet it's you know people
are like well i'll eat organic and drink
water like you share in the same air as
everybody else
like you you actually cannot be an
island we have to do this together we
have to have access to it together
so that's a bit of what what i would
like to see in the future
i love that that's awesome
and so uh if you we can talk about the
future beautiful vision or we can also
switch on to um
the adjacent possible which always
honestly interweaves the beautiful
future because it's not like yeah
i wanted to go on your thread a little
bit uh to to re-kind of
re-reiterate what i heard from that
um the common threads between
what i'm envisioning and
what you are
kind of imagining is the
[Music]
ability for the average person
to contribute
to science um through
through a system so we we get
some type of system in place and
then the average person who has
maybe they have cancer and they want to
contribute their
findings to other people who have the
same type of cancer that they found
through a system they can send
all of these their their data to
someone they trust that is going to
decentralize and maybe like make make
some type of scientific experiment
based off of a um yeah like
you know not having to rely on
institutions
as much but to be able to
um be like i want something done
i'm really interested in this like can i
find other people that are interested in
this let's check my social media
networks and
does anyone want to have you know too
interested in this you are you are great
boom okay let's all get our resources
together and do something about it right
like
that that kind of idea
of almost like i'm imagining like a
patreon almost or like a gofundme
style platform for
science um
almost i guess more like a gofundme like
here is this
here's something that needs to get done
who wants to contribute and then people
volunteer whatever things that they can
into that system um
does that kind of does that make sense
at all is that close to uh and i think
that's something that is absolutely
adjacently possible
like having that's that's the json
possible yeah i mean it's it's huge but
it'd like to turn it into the adjacent
possible right to get 10 000 people
who have any condition let's sort like
pick a condition ten thousand people
with that condition
or ten thousand people had a loved one
who died from that condition or
something like that
right and having instead of yes we're
gonna fundraise and give it to the
cancer foundation
or autism speaks which is a horrible
foundation like having the actual people
say no
here's where we want the research to go
um right
like autistic people don't want the
research to go into curing it because it
doesn't need to be cured we need to know
how to like
live with neurotypical people and how to
like live our best lives
and so fundraising that money and
deciding where that money goes for
research
without them needing like they have to
report back the null science but not
their scientists they get to to do the
study right they would put in the
just like a grant application which one
of these do we want to
have and then we have access to that and
for the data point so we can actually
also have a
that's probably not doable 100 000 one
or the other
data points is a lot of money but be
able to have just a platform
of like you said a patreon account like
everyone pick one
condition and start with that bring in
the it has to be one that has ten
thousand people
right so not probably some genetic
condition that's one in a million
but something that is
you know one form of cancer breast
cancer and
bringing those people in and saying hey
here is your
what did you do for it because you can
also that's that's part of it is knowing
that you're a data point you're living
your life and you get diagnosed you've
already shared a lot of your information
if there's that system to do it in and
then
you're also sharing you're not in a
double-blind study where someone else is
deciding that you take this medication
or this medication but you're going to
be choosing to
do the treatments that you do and you're
going to choose the diet that you choose
and just to be able to know that even if
you made the wrong decisions even if
your doctors made the wrong decisions
that
the next generations will get that
information i know that i would like
that
i would like to feel that if my kid
inherits any of my conditions that even
if i'm
not doing the ideal things you can't in
our current system
that whatever i'm doing i can pass that
on i can pass on that information
yeah i think that's so important the
knowing that
everything that you're doing is not for
for
for not and like it really is
like having this continuity between
generations
of information and
something that is it's not just in a
pile of papers that you need to sort
through but it's actually
made sense of in like a database
somewhere that can be accessed and
real real knowledge can be gleaned from
the data and knowledge that's that's
um i was also thinking about
how how to motivate
people to
how to motivate an influx of money other
than
um by the people that just have it
or like by the people that like hey care
about my my condition
and this kind of merges pretty well with
another
idea i had that was um
fandom altruistic competitions
so i'll i'll kind of expand on that
imagine an artist or a singer
or someone who has like lady gaga who
has her monsters
um actually well this is way better um
in k-pop they already this is already
happening this actually
was where i got this idea but um these
k-pop
stars um their fandoms have
self-organized
and are actually competing to gain honor
for their artists by
donating things and by um doing
altruistic
stuff almost like um in the same way
that like a church would
um kind of you know do community service
like these
fandoms are doing altruistic good
in the name of their artist
so i was thinking about this and like
that's a really interesting dynamic of
what if
we could create a system such that
um like red sox versus yankees
right like while the game is going on
while there's like a real
competition there can be a side
competition of
who can contribute the most
towards a altruistic good
and i'm wondering if that can
fall into the same category of science
or or that it might be too much of a
stretch but
the maybe the users of this app
can have certain things that they are
passionate about and um
and then i'll all of the
you know whatever i don't know i think
it's a little bit a little bit of a
stretch but i don't know if there's
anything there for you
what was coming up for me while you were
saying that was uh there's i can't
remember what the name of the
website is it's they basically raise
money by having
um caught like you win something it's a
raffle right so
it's always like it's kind of like a
prize home or a a tiny home
or an experience with a celebrity is is
also what is happening
and so having it that piece of it where
celebrities like hey
you get front row tickets to lady gaga
because she cares about breast cancer
and so she's going to put that for
breast cancer and like when girl guides
give
sell their cookies and there's like a
prize for the one who sells the most in
the truth they're all selling and
they're all kind of trying to get it but
only one person is going to win that
we're having something along those lines
where there's like this experience
that is amazing and if you happen to be
one of the people who brings in more
people or more money
these are those are the two roles that
you get right and it's the top three or
top
top five to do it but it's the celebrity
the person who has the thing that you
want that is
you know donated and there could be any
kind of number of businesses
right various levels the one i'm talking
about it's very high level prizes and so
the tickets it's like you buy like you
know the tickets are
a dollar but you have to start at 50
right so you buy like 50 for a dollar
yeah 50 for 50
or and it goes up from there and so i'm
like if i'm not spending 500
dollars i'm not gonna have enough
entries to probably win anyway so why
even
why even pray but right but i'll but
i'll
play the lottery that one's big enough
that i'm like okay
if i want 100 million dollars i know
what i'm doing with it
yeah having something along those lines
where for people who
have the fan base and have a cause they
care about
that they can raise money
in that way yeah like is there is there
something there
like are there can there be
a mobilization of these fan bases that
are
that's not just a mobilization towards
give me more money um but more of
mobilization towards like let's do
something good
let's provide meaning in people's lives
let's um you know feel
like what you're doing is
is impactful in the world
i think i don't know i i maybe that's
a time for another another solution
raising of some some other
kind of mechanism there but i think
with science
i think it's i think just
the digital age and
having normalizing the
the ability to participate
and interact with science
in a easy way is going to be
the next step because right now science
is
so institutionalized and walled off and
like we need to
get some way to
communicate two-way street with science
directly the average person
um i think one of the things
in that vein of getting science
accessible to
is to pick to have a platform where you
pick
topics that are the most important i'm
guessing covet 19 might be one of the
ones that's the most important right now
like this is costing everybody that
people don't have access to science and
they don't have access to trust and who
do you trust right
how does that work that as studies are
published
people are able to say yes that one's
powerful i want that one explained
and then having it be made available in
a crowd-sourced infographic way where
it's like okay you were going to explain
how this was actually done
so taking something that is very um
similar to use for like legal platform
but like that is
in language that is not accessible and
in fact it's very unaccessible when you
talk to scientists they do not talk like
their scientific papers
they you know it's like they have to
make it in that way so it gets published
and then they understand it they can
have a conversation when they're having
a conversation it's not like that
and so being able to take that
translated into regular english and even
into
like a explain this to a fourth grader
right um
in you know with cartoons and like they
took this and they injected into four
people here was the placebo and here was
and here's what happened from it
um to be able to
put the call out for the volunteers in
all of those areas right that if you
have to pay everyone for the
infographics it's probably not going to
be
accessible we're going to spend more
money on that than on the science but if
there's
ais that could help you with that right
if it's if i could do embryo graphics
because it was super easy i know those
platforms already exist they're just
expensive and so to be able to have
something like excel meets or you know
google doc
spreadsheet meets an infographic that's
super beautiful that
basically anyone can do and anyone can
have access to that data all the way
down right like not just the infographic
but also where did you get that
information from
and infographics they're able to be
played with you're going to say
hey what if we change this metric and
what if we change this one and that's a
lot of different things but
no no i love that that's right down the
line of like where
it's like it's like this
ever since i learned about this
technology there's always this like
kind of like like exponential curve
till like this this end horizon
of this ai helping everything and like
i always just like oh why don't we just
get to say ai to do that and it's like
well we have to get the ai working first
that's
that's the first step to get all of this
done so i i'm like
reluctant to say like that's gonna be
easy but like
eventually that's going to be easy where
you'll be able to just talk to the ai
and the ais can actually go and make the
infographic for you
kind of thing or like the ai can create
an infographic
based off of the science itself like it
there's it has the capability of doing
that theoretically once it's built out
so that's really exciting but
until then i think
you need to get people
who understand these studies
to well let's see let's think about it
the people who have made the studies and
have translated it to this
super jargony unaccessible english
they they're doing that because they're
incentivized to do that to get it into a
journal
that can get published that sounds smart
and
what if they were also incentivized to
make it simple
so in order to like making making a
in the same way getting published
in a public space that everyone can see
that is almost like a patreon type thing
where
if they're really good at um
you know explaining complex science
then they get donations from people or
they get a
people subscribe to their their patreon
feed where they are cranking out
these infographics or simple summaries
of complex information
um i'm trying to think of like an
incentive mechanism
that can drive people
i think scientists need patreon
incentives the eureka moment
is the thing for scientists and then
they have to spend all of their time and
get
right all of these grants in order to
get to that eureka moment
and then they have to put it into
whatever speak in order for it to get
published
having a platform where they can where
they're able to share in that journey
in a way that is like okay we got this
data because it's also
you create a study and you have to
troubleshoot it the entire time and then
you're kind of going back and pretending
you didn't troubleshoot it while also
honoring that you troubleshoot
shot it and so to be able to share that
and be like okay this is the data we're
getting and wait
no wait the petri dishes aren't growing
at all so we need to go back and to the
drawing board and recreate it
and be able to share in that that's
important part of this the science
people to have access to the raw data so
that people can play with it and then
they're published in a way
that's in their own language and someone
to help them with that right because the
scientists themselves aren't necessarily
the best at explaining it
but they're they're coming up with the
eureka moment and that moment of
creating the the experiment
that's getting that novel new piece of
information to be able to just
share that novel piece of new
information as it arises
and this is not the solution raising for
it but when we have ubi
when we have our needs met scientists
choose to be scientists to be scientists
right like they're there for so they
know their food's covered they don't
need that money coming in constantly
they just need to do the science and if
they have access to it where they don't
have to be part of the universities they
have access to a laboratory
then we you know you don't remove all
the incentives so that
the people who are focusing on science
are there because they want to be
scientists but that's probably not
feasible
but a platform where they're able to
share in that
crowdsourcing and even open source
science of like well why aren't
i can run an experiment right like
there's those experiments people have
run of um
plants right by your computer and plants
far away and things like that like
crowdsource science where it's like okay
if i can put in my geographical location
my long tube latitude all of that and
i'm growing five plants and i'm doing
a double blinder of some growing here
and some growing there
but so do thousands of people around the
world
that's much better information than
having one person do it
uh you know even in a laboratory it's
completely controlled because you can't
really control the variables to that
right high level to be able to say hey
what are the kind of experiments that we
can run together
and see is this doable i mean there's a
lot of um
what is the word uh like
alternative medicine right right
powerful than the
the medicine that's out there but the
medicine seltzer is for profit so it's
like right in vitamin c cured cancer
we're not going to hear about it because
they don't want it to cure cancer they
don't want they might stop it in its
tracks right so to be able to say
no like just sharing that information to
be able to act
on that experiment to say i don't know
if i was going to get cancer or not but
hey i take vitamin c every day
and see who gets cancer who doesn't get
cancer what is it
based on all that and that's a long
experiment but i'm sure there's some you
can test that are
yeah does this help you or hurt you
yeah i think that that's kind of where
that
end asymptote like
end goal of with like a system
that you can put in your
personal data about x y or z
anything and it's your data
that you can choose to give or
sell or whatever you want to other
people
that same way in the science side of
things you can
show that you can like give the
information
to um to science that you
have vitamin c every day or that you
have gotten cancer you have not blah
blah and then
as long as the data is understood
by the system then you can
extract value out of it so that
it seems to me as if once we have a
system
that people
trust enough to
give their own personal data
into it and
possibly earn a basic income just by
volunteering information about
themselves um
then that can be an
outlet for open source
science in terms of um
getting a lot of data points and then
making
kind of finding out
from a huge pool of data making
good kind of um
yeah pulling pulling good information
out of that and
making conclusions that you wouldn't
normally have
um i think that'd be really important
but is there a way to just hyper
specify make that really specific in the
next five to ten years
of something that like this is just a
science
platform all the information you put in
here
goes to science and
you get out of this x like just the
the the fact that i mean is that a good
enough motivator the fact that
your data is going in post it on
instagram right if it's as easy as hey
here's my meal here's this here's that
and it's just what you're offering
because right not everyone's going to
give their meal not everyone's going to
give everything
you can also go back and extrapolate and
say actually want more information on
your meals are you willing to do that
right
but i think also what is also coming up
is a platform of crowdsourced
experiments and more particularly
looking at
easy experiments that haven't been run
that could be run i mean i don't know if
you're right
i always like watching conspiracy theory
documentaries because i'm looking for
the grain of truth that it's based on
and there's like no grain of truth in
flat earth like
if you watch the documentaries it's like
we're gonna run this experiment and none
of them work right
so so let's honor that it could be real
what are the experiments that could be
run
and then yes if the flat earthers still
want to hold on to theirs it's like okay
no no we're all gonna run these
experiments all over the world and
report our data
one of the other experiments is
something came up for me in university
is i was very obsessed with trying to
eat um
organic and eating wild salmon because
the farmed salmon was killing the wild
salmon so like i needed
warm salmon i was staying away from it
and i went to ubc which is where like
david suzuki is
is a professor and um
lives right nearby and part of the
suzuki foundation wild salmon only wild
salmon farm salmon is horrible it's
where a lot of the farmed salmon is
is is on bc's coast and so the idea is
that the sea lice from the farmed salmon
are killing the wild salmon as they go
through so i did a study on this in
university
that because the the pro farm side says
this does not make sense
because the lice don't swim and when the
farm when the wild salmon are coming
through
it doesn't work before the wild salmon
side is like no no
no it's the currents they take them
there it would literally be a 500
experiment to test it you release
particles into the water and see where
they end up
right and study that no one wants to run
it because the farm side doesn't want to
show that
they're wrong and the wild side doesn't
want to show that they're wrong and that
was like this
big aha moment in university of like
what
no of course we want the science but
neither of the sides won but we want it
as the concern
is the people with that information so
we could we could
crowdsource and crowdfund that right and
be like okay
if the suzuki foundation doesn't want to
know that and the farmed
salmon people don't want to know that we
can run that experiment and see
right he can keep asking questions about
wait okay what is the life cycle of the
lice and why are why do all the wild
salmon have all of these lice on them
and yet not from the farm salmon where
is it coming from
like to actually think of these somewhat
easy experiments
they could be run run them and publish
them and and look for those things look
for the ones that aren't billion dollar
million dollar studies
with us but just like huh
that should be interesting that sounds i
mean that sounds like a perfect
opportunity for
a gofundme
style platform for science
um in that like all it takes is somebody
who's
really passionate about it for someone
to see oh
okay both of these people are not going
to do this
but this is something that needs to be
done like
i'm going to make a case for this
and show people that this needs to be
done
and like they have that their own
intrinsic motivation
to create the the gofundme to create or
the
go science me i don't know you call it
whatever you want but like
to create the the
listing that shows okay we need
to to do this experiment we're gonna do
it like this
and we're going to do this all we need
is x amount of money
like share on social media and like
people can just be like oh that's great
yeah boom do that i want that to happen
like i'll share you money
or like oh somebody sees it and says oh
i can make you a quick little video
if you want me to to make this more
exposed because
you know and then they contribute to
your little science thing
um yeah i can see that being
a good mechanism um
so how can you make it down into needs
like for the salmon one yeah
we need it we need the place to do it we
need the boat right
then the meeting like that's not that
and so if someone donates a boat you
don't have to rent one like
right you get a boat but like you know
for the day for the day and
the people's labor and the people to act
to actually look at the data when it's
done
um and that's even that because if the
scientists themselves are looking at the
data they can kind of skew it with their
own bias whereas if
you don't know what data you're looking
at you're just working the numbers you
don't know what placebo non-placebo is
right you don't know
there is not a controlled study in that
necessarily but like finding
that there's ways to do it so it's even
better science yeah
and it's cheaper because we're together
and
i wonder
because now i'm thinking of like well
okay how do we get
the funding to create a platform that
can
get funding for this like oh we can make
it
we can make a indiegogo or something
like
a gofundme for this project
then it just gets really it gets very
much
solution in general is that right like
it's like yeah yeah amazing ideas you
could create
with ten thousand people a hundred
thousand dollars but first we have to
create the platform that gets you the
ten thousand people and the hundred
thousand dollars and then we can write
all of them right boom but it's like
that because like a lot of the ideas
you've come up with i've come up with
other people have come up with and it's
like they don't they either already
existed in the world and they failed
they exist in the world and they're not
that great or they're
like 20 people are working on them at
the same time and it's like no there has
to be that meta solution that's slightly
higher of like how do we come together
and actually create it so it works
and that's part of the 10 000 is not
just
like if i won the lottery tomorrow and i
can make any of these ideas
great and i can hire someone to market
it and i can hire someone but
it's not as powerful as having ten
thousand people come together because
you know you already have the number of
people
to make it usable right because we've
got ten thousand people not just funds
that platform
but also to say yeah and i'm willing to
put in ten dollars then you get to
create all of them
and you don't have to refine that 10 000
every time right like maybe like no one
showed up for the science one today
besides you which i totally appreciate
that it's because it's it's a hard one
it's like i don't know science
you might not have shown up in science
right but this has been a really great
conversation yeah
um that's what was my point about i
remember
but just like you might not fund the
science one but if you're on this
website putting in the ten dollars on
them we vote for the science one the
science one gets funded or maybe yours
is history right like or the i mean the
four powerful solutions i'm like
i've been obsessed with them for the
last weeks and like if we figure out the
shelter
we figure out community and how to
create like you know where you can park
your little tiny home and how you can
create a community with that and if you
need to leave you can find a new one
and we solve food there's an app that
you can grow food with connect with
other people
ai or not right you can just use our
crowdsource and
education because children need to be
educated and school's not really working
under copay 19. so if i know my kid can
get
her basics and her desire like her
wanted learning done
anywhere then no one has control over
you if your food shelter
and education of your children are
within your own control then you have
ubi
yeah effectively and you can work within
these communities and the community
itself has a source of income
and so it's like i'm upset i'm like i
don't know how that just materializes
but i'm also in this space of we're just
getting off of
such amazing this anti-mlm i don't know
if you know mlm is the multi-level
multi-level marketing yeah yeah that are
like they're designed to fail one
percent of people break like get profit
and that's not like they make it right
they break even and get you know their
dollar of profit off of it and like
there's something there about that model
though that's like right so you come be
part of the ten thousand you're
recruiting recruiting but it's not about
you may you get to retire in five years
we're all gonna retire in five years
we're all gonna retire in ten years and
it's not off the backs of other people
it's off this pool of ingenuity this
pool of
of resources like you get to put in ten
dollars and you get out thousands that
doesn't work in gaming it doesn't work
with charity
but it works with ingenuity right it's
like we can create
all of these solutions and change
everything we don't need to go through
the governments and go through that we
need to be legal but we don't we can
create anything
anything that has to have a solution
with ten thousand people and hundred
thousand dollars
i love that are you are you in contact
with um
julie friedman steele of world future
society at all or no
no have you ever i want to introduce you
guys because she
is creating uh within world future
society
um she's creating an organization called
sif type 1
which is um based off the kardashians
scale of like
utilizing all like it's like what what
what can a sieve type one look like
we're at a sift type zero right now and
like sift type one
is like it's like game a game b kind of
mentality right um but every week
every wednesday they have um civ type 1
meetings where people
there's like you know 10 to 30 people
that all
get together and they talk about
creating tangible solutions in the world
that can lead to a sieve type one
it's not as structured as a solutions
raising which i think is
where your idea can merge
really well with that community in terms
of like it gives them structure of what
to talk about
and to really beat up these ideas and
then to
um kind of bring it to life and so i'd
love to actually set up a conversation
with you guys
um to see if there's any kind of
crossover or collaboration
that could kind of join between the
communities
yeah i'm down i'm down for any
connection with the world and this is
like what was i was
i woke up angry this spring because one
of the people who usually is here was
like i need to take a break i'm losing
my job i'm losing you know like i need a
roof over my head i'm like and then one
of my other friends i'm actually sitting
through an mlm pitch this saturday
because she was like would you come be
part of my zoom calm like yeah anything
you're up to i know you're a world
changer it was like oh and essential
oils right
but like there are these people who and
she has connections and the fact she
can't make a living with a patreon
account doing what she's doing in the
world
is like right because there isn't enough
and this guy from from uh kenya who has
this beautiful j10 village and they just
need 500
a month and they would be able to like
not have to fundraise and just be able
to deal
with with feeding their 50 people for
right and it's like there's all these
solutions and it's all these influencers
out
there i'm like to be able to do what
mlms do but actually
like be like actually guarantee a good
future because we're going to create it
together you don't have to be anything
you're not
you don't have to if you're not a
recruiter that's not your job
other people are the word of mouth
people other people are those people
and find a way to bring that together
and part of it is meeting with all the
people who are already doing the world
changing things and are and how do those
things move together because we're not
in competition
right because it feels like we are it's
like we're already in cooperation
how do we assist each other solution
raising is designed that anyone can do
it
anyone can show up to these but also
anyone could just host one i'm like
steal it
do it right it's not stealing like just
do it franchise it and so like
i have this vision of like one celebrity
one time doing a solution raising
with their celebrity friends and then
offering like being like and
not take our idea and do it but
do your own solution raising right right
for education right now with covet
everyone's like i don't know what about
the teachers and the job i'm like if we
had 10 000 people have solution raisings
we would come up with an idea for a
powerful platform then we all feel like
we created it we'd all put in 10
maybe 10 a month per kid where you get
basically an
uh at home amazing education
that is you know connected with your
like peers and friends
you know what your bubble is and you can
play together and be more safe
and you know also honoring that some
people need to go to work how do we get
those needs met like
talking about what your needs are right
like what's working and not working for
you and how do we make the next step so
that you get a better life
keep doing that gets us to game b it
gets us to whatever
sb01 right like it gets us to that next
that next level yeah that's so true
so true i yeah i i definitely want to
introduce you guys
and see if there's anything that can
come of that because i think
the joining of
um efforts when
the efforts are the same it's the same
goal you know it just kind of
doesn't make sense for everyone to be
doing it all on their own without
their own like just combined ideas
combined things like
merge and and in you know power and
numbers kind of thing
so um absolutely cool i'd have to say a
year ago i hadn't heard of game b
and this person i'm sitting through the
mlm thing for was one of the only people
i was so happy i met her
and i met ramsay from common planet like
oh my god like
like you have to hold on to them because
you're like oh no other people
it's like there's so many people who are
changing the world it's like
oh i actually could i could not i could
not do this and the world would still be
okay
like it's like but i'm gonna because
it's fun right it's still
there's all the ideas like i don't have
to create the tech cooperative i don't
have to create the technology because
other people are creating it
i can just have the conversation i can
just do the next thing and give people
permission to do their thing like
when i watch the podcast that you send
me at me and i was like
i hate that i don't finish my thoughts
like no one can follow my thoughts
and i'm like you know what you know how
many people are out there that are
exactly like that
put yourself out in the world like it's
like i'm still creating powerful things
within my capacity
and that's what i want to give people
permission to do show up fuck up till
you get it right like it's
it's not easy love that it's actually
there's
nobody that accepts you in doing that
yeah yeah show up again the next day
like you guys were like you guys are you
are horrible
you get a zero i i'm judging myself
based on that
and yeah it's like all right yeah and
i'm gonna
i'm 100 okay with putting it out there
because it'll give somebody permission
to show up and do their thing that's it
you just gotta
get out there and create something
yeah yeah all right well you're at the
hour i'll stop
recording so we can okay and
thanks jared for hanging out oh wait
wait before i do that
usually also because there's more people
go through what do you think is the most
powerful thing we could do with ten
thousand people and a hundred thousand
dollars
for science what is the most most
powerful adjacent possible ten
thousand people and a hundred thousand
dollars um
build i'm i'm defining this
as a something that is
possible right now um and i would say
build a platform with that ten thousand
dollar hundred thousand dollars
um build a platform that allows those 10
000 people to
input data
about themselves basically to the the
idea of
open sourcing science to those people
but like
those 10 000 people with a hundred
thousand dollars
making a um crowdsourced
science platform that people can
contribute
to i think would be really powerful
awesome thanks um my most powerful for
ten thousand hundred dollars because you
have the most impact on my life
is to pick one condition in my case
probably chronic fatigue because there's
a lot of
at 19 people that are showing you that
are ending up they have something very
similar to code too yeah
and it's something that doctors don't
take you seriously
we all take each other seriously and
it's like there's something that would
work and yet
what works one person doesn't work for
another picking one condition though
having 10 000 people with that condition
who are fundraising whatever instead of
it going to someone else
we will fund it then we if they're not
going to fund it
we will fund and we will decide what
that funding looks like and we can put
our data in right that might be the
automatic thing which we're already
doing in small groups right and it could
be something that could be started with
a facebook group that is or
a you know discord server of hey bring
in the 10 000 people and then we have a
crowdfunding campaign we have 100 000 of
like what experiment do we want to run
yeah but a platform is where we want to
because then anyone with any condition
can come on and be part of
creating that that community of people
who understand you and can just be
camaraderie and also
can actually fund and do science
together
yeah i love that right all right thank
you jared now we will stop the recording